## **AHSAN SHARIF UDDIN**

House No - 35, Road No - 01, Sector 13, Uttara • Dhaka -1230, Bangladesh +880 1673452937 • ahsan.sharif452@gmail.com



### **OBJECTIVE**

Having enthusiasm for working in the talent acquisition and organizational development where my strategic goals can add value to the organization as well as to plays a vital role in employer branding.

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

Dedicated professional with proven skills and experience in talent acquisition, employee relations, employer branding and learning & development. A team player with effective interpersonal communication skills and a strong work ethic. Strong enthusiast mind with an MBA focused on Human Resource Management from North South University.

### **EDUCATION**

North South University (Dhaka, Bangladesh) May 2016 - April 2019

Masters of Business Administration, Major in Human Resources Management.

CGPA: 2.78/4.00 Major GPA: 3.22 / 4.00

Daffodil Institute of IT (Under National University) (Dhaka, Bangladesh) March 2010 – December 2014

Bachelor of Business Administration, Major in Marketing

GPA: 3.16/4.00





IAMUNA GROUP

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Jamuna Group (Dhaka, Bangladesh) January 2020 - Present

Junior Executive - HR & Admin

Website: https://jamunagroup.com.bd/

Jamuna Group is one of the largest Bangladeshi industrial conglomerates. The industries under this conglomerate include Textiles, Chemicals, Leather, Motor cycles, Consumer products, Media, Advertisement etc. Responsibilities:

- Assist with day to day operations of the HR functions and duties
- Support in recruitment activities like shortlisting CVs, sending interview calls, interview coordination.
- Explores the market best practices in the recruitment and staffing and implement appropriate best practices in the organization
- To maintain management guidelines by preparing, updating, and recommending human resource policies and procedure
- Present shortlisted candidates and provide detailed profile summaries
- Keep track of market trends and best practices for effective placement of prospective candidates

### LankaBangla Investments Limited (LBIL) (Dhaka, Bangladesh) March 2015 - May 2015

Intern, Business Development

Website: http://www.lankabangla-investments.com/

LankaBangla Investments Limited (LBIL) a fully owned subsidiary of LankaBangla Finance Limited, one of the leading NonBanking Financial Institutions in Bangladesh. LBIL is engaged in providing investment banking services and Investment Management Services for its clients.

### Responsibilities:

- Maintained relationship approach with prospective customers.
- Working in Excel with the collection of data for reputed financial organization and stock market rate.
- Learning investment banking by co-workers.

### **LEADERSHIP & EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

JAAGO Foundation (Dhaka, Bangladesh) September 2016

Volunteer

Event Title: Great Kindness Challenge.

On the 4th of September, 2016, Volunteer for Bangladesh, will celebrate the "Great Kindness Challenge". With flowers and cards, the students of the JAAGO Foundation and the volunteers of JAAGO foundation will thank the Police Department, Fire Fighters, Journalists, Social Workers and some of the heroes who are hardly thanked for their continuous service and dedication towards the society.









#### TRAINING & WORKSHOPS

### HR Analytics & Dashboard with Excel - Thriving Skills

Issued June 2020

Website: https://thrivingskill.com/

#### **Topics Covered:**

Learn the Global HR Metrics, Learn the most useful excel functions/formulas to derive the metrics, Design the HR Report Format in PivotTable, Learn the Most Unconventional ways of Data Visualization, Sketch your HR Dashboard in the Excel Canvas, Customize the Dashboard Widgets, Dashboard Pro Tips, The Big Project: HR Analytics Dashboard.

### **Bring Data to Life Excel Dashboard** - Thriving Skills

Issued May 2020

Website: https://thrivingskill.com/

#### **Topics Covered:**

Understanding Dashboard Architecture, Learn the PivotTable & Excel Chart in Depth, Creative use of Slicers.

### Employee Engagement - Udemy

Issued August 2019

Website: https://www.udemy.com/

### **Topics Covered:**

Introduction to Employee Engagement, The Employee Engagement Imperative, The Nature of Work, The Appreciative Culture, The Holistic Structure

### Excel - Module 1 (Basic) - North South University

Issued April 2018

Website: http://www.northsouth.edu/

## **Topics Covered:**

Introduction to Excel, Basic formatting techniques, Math & Statistical Functions, Date & Time Functions, Text functions.

### **Mastering Effective Communication – LEAD**

Issued October 2017

Website: http://www.lead.vision/

### **Topics Covered:**

Understanding key elements of communication, Learning the inspiring factor in communication, Identify and overcome key barriers to communication.

## Art and Practice of Leadership - Bangladesh Youth Leadership Center (BYLC)

Issued December 2016

Website: https://bylc.org/

### **Topics Covered:**

Leadership Skill development, Communication skill development, Professional thinking for solving problems, Adapt to diverse learning environments, Group discussion effectively, Observing capacity buildup, Managing power to competitive job market.

#### **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

Skills: Proficient in Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint, Word.

Interests: Socializing with friends and family, playing football and cricket on weekly basis, reading books, solving puzzles,

listening to music, visiting new places and spending more time on learning.

Languages: Bangla (native); English (advanced)

## **REFERENCES**

#### Dr. M. Khasro Miah

Professor, Department of Management North South University (Dhaka, Bangladesh)

Mobile No: +8801755593901

Email: khasro.miah@northsouth.edu

Relation: Academic

# Dr. Tamgid Ahmed Chowdhury

Associate Professor, Department of Marketing & International Business

North South University (Dhaka, Bangladesh)

Mobile No: +8801712181306

Email: tamgid.ahmed@northsouth.edu

Relation: Academic









